ERIC GELDMACHER

GIS ANALYST



eric.geldmacher@outlook.com



(508) 566-5003



Westport, MA



SECURITY CLEARANCE

SECRET / 2024

EDUCATION

AIR UNIVERSITY Eng Tech 2018

UCONN Geographic Information Science 2022

TRAINING

USAF - GIS / CAD Training / 850 hrs

USAF - Leadership School / 250 hrs

ESRI - Advanced GIS Course / 80 hrs

ESRI - Various Online Training / 50 hrs

ESRI - User Conference (x2) / 90 hrs

VDCI - Civil 3D 101 / 30 hrs

V2PMP - Project Management / 50 hrs

SOFTWARE

ESRI - ArcMap / ArcGIS Pro/ ArcScene

AutoCAD - Civil3D / Map3D

Adobe - Photoshop / Acrobat

Trimble- Business Center / Pathfinder

Google - Docs / Sheets / Drive

Microsoft - Word / Excel / Powerpoint

SKILLS

GIS • AutoCAD • Map Production Spatial

Analysis • Data Management

Cartography • Graphic Design

Model Builder • Training • Mentoring Documentation Request • Management

Project / Personnel Management

Process Improvements • Planning

Briefing • Reporting • Quality Control

Customer Service • Computer Science

SUMMARY

Eric Geldmacher is a veteran of the U.S. Air Force with an Associate's Degree in Engineering Technology, and a 6-year background in GIS, AutoCAD, and surveying. He is an experienced GIS professional who has managed large mapping operations in support of National Defense initiatives.

WORK EXPERIENCE



GEOSPATIAL SUPPORT MANAGER

US Air Force - JBLM Public Works, WA • 2019 - 2020

- Coordinated with scientists, engineers, and planners to develop creative GIS solutions
- Provided geospatial support to 400+ staff members across six divisions in JBLM Public Works
- Produced maps for emergency, environmental, and community improvement projects
- Regulated and improved data quality and organization in an enterprise geodatabase
- Managed robotic, optical and GPS surveys for public works projects and operations



SURVEY OPERATIONS MANAGER

US Air Force - Guantanamo Bay, Cuba • 2019

- Managed the production of custom maps in support of international military operations
- Planned and supervised topographic and 3D survey missions throughout Cuba
- Delivered mission briefings, organized workloads, and delegated tasks / assignments
- Responsibly handled classified information in a highly secured environment



GIS TRAINING MANAGER

US Air Force - JBLM Public Works, WA • 2016 - 2019

- Created cartographic and quality control standards for scaled map production
- Trained and mentored 30+ military personnel in advanced GIS disciplines and best practices
- Conducted regular training on spatial analysis, data processing, drafting, and surveying
- Improved and documented training curriculum for a successful turnover



AUTOCAD DRAFTSMAN

US Air Force - Doha, Qatar • 2016

- Designed transportation infrastructure for Kuwait International Airport
- Prepared and published statement of works (SOW) to initiate new construction projects
- Post-processed site surveys and LiDAR to render 3D models for planning and development
- Documented and implemented new standard operating procedures for onbaording staff



GIS ANALYST

US Air Force / JBLM Public Works, WA • 2014 - 2016

- Delivered 400+ custom maps and data requests on demand with mission critical intelligence
- Identified trends and potential risks through spatial analysis & geoprocessing
- Provided timely assessments and reports to key decision makers and stakeholders
- Consistently exceed customer expectations and delivered outstanding service